Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer London, United Kingdom

+447487553781konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

PROFILE

Self-motivated software developer with six years of experience in the field and four years of experience in Java development. Motivated to participate as a team player and develop well-tested applications using a continuous delivery approach. I highly enjoy carrying out profound research and learning about new technologies, alongside looking for ways to improve my work.

Programming Skills

• Languages: Java, TypeScript Technologies: Spring Framework, Angular, Hibernate, Junit, Mockito

• Tools: AWS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, Jenkins, Maven, IntelliJ, Redis

EXPERIENCE

• Monese London, United Kingdom Mar 2019 - Present Software Engineer

- Reduced costs by systematically improving software performance and decreasing operating costs. For one application, its monthly operating cost was decreased by 50%.
- o Increased revenue by identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursuing a solution for a single customer led to the identification of a significant gap in profit.
- As a part of the Pricing team, delivered business priorities by completing a new, annual pricing functionality on-time and without any significant issues. Additionally, I led research on breaking a monolithic application into a single responsibility micro-service.
- As a part of the Joint Accounts team, I designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts feature.

• Monese Tallinn, Estonia Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

Software Engineer

- As a part of the Smart Transactions team, I improved the scalability of micro-services by separating the read and write operation of the database.
- Successfully migrated 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service. As a result, the average response time decreased from 60ms to 5ms.
- Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling. Helped improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.
- o As a part of the Recurring Payments team, I designed and developed a micro-service with a test coverage of up to 80%.

 Codeborne Tallinn, Estonia Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

Software Developer

- As a part of the Banking team, I advocated for clean, robust, and maintainable code while promoting through code reviews, pair programming, and test-driven development.
- Increased the team's productivity by sharing my peers' development tricks.
- Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.

• Knowit Tallinn, Estonia

Software Developer

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

- Employee of the Q4, 2016.
- o Developed a full-stack, web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.

EDUCATION

• Tallinn University

Estonia

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (BSc); Computer Science; GPA: 4.73/5; cum laude

2014 - 2017

- Thesis "The Development of a Self-study Web Application Using Angular and Spring Boot"
- Achievement stipend
- Specialisation stipend